Andrew BATES

abates@omeganetserv.com 4 Trinity Court, Andover, MA 01810 http://github.com/abates 719 200 1191

VALUE STATEMENT

Highly motivated network and security engineer with experience in complex enterprise networks and multi-tiered application environments. Experience in network design, operations and security including network policy auditing and evaluation. Additional experience in network routing, data center switching, Virtual Private Networks (VPNs), and Software Defined Networks (SDNs).

Significant leadership experience in large cross functional teams. This includes performing as a technical team lead in multiple positions and lead architect for major projects.

SKILLS AND INTERESTS

- Programming Golang, Python, Ruby, PERL, C, C++
- Network Operations Arista, Juniper, Cisco
- Network Security firewall configuration, policy enforcement, VPN
- Devops Ansible, Docker, Kubernetes

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF COLORADO AT COLORADO SPRINGS

Master of Science in Computer Science

JANUARY 2009 - MAY 2015

Graduated with Master of Science degree in Computer Science. Graduating GPA 4.0

COLORADO TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

BSCS completed in the spring of 2005. Graduated with 3.5 GPA.

Colorado Springs, CO APRIL 2001 - MARCH 2005

WORK EXPERIENCE

Andrew Bates Consulting, LLC Managing Member

Leesburg, VA
DECEMBER 2014 - DECEMBER 2017

OPIC Tableau Server Infrastructure

Responsible for installation and documentation of Tableau server as part of a big data analysis project for the Overseas Private Investment Corporation (OPIC). This included integrating with existing single sign on systems as well as building appropriate backup and housekeeping tasks. Was also responsible for drafting the operations and maintanence manual for the Tableau server infrastructure at OPIC.

Loudoun Youth Salesforce Consulted with Loudoun Youth to deploy Salesforce in order to manage registrations and contacts for the Loudoun Youth summer programs. This included developing a custom Salesforce APEX application to manage registration forms and collect registration data.

RedArc Group Consulted for RedArc Group to develop several customer proposals. This work included analyzing customer requirements, researching solutions and assembling proposal documentation for the customer.

APPLIED NETWORK SOLUTIONS Software Engineer

Columbia, MD August 2013 - March 2015

NetVistra FSDB

Designed, built and delivered a first release data analytics product. NetVistra FSDB was built on elastic-search and a customized version of elasticsearch kibana. Product development efforts included setting up automated install ISO and automated package builds for all components of the product.

NetVistra Splunk

Responsible for developing customized tools for the Splunk Framework. This included custom scripted inputs in Python as well as custom dashboards using Splunk's advanced XML, Javascript, HTML and CSS.

ANS SDN Offerings

Worked with team to investigate SDN technology and ways to leverage early SDN implementations for ANS customer networks. Proposed ways to include SDN capabilities into existing ANS product offerings.

VERIZON MARCH 2005-JULY 2013

Global Network Planning

Principal Member of Technical Staff

Colorado Springs, CO MAY 2012 - JULY 2013

Responsible for developing network architecture plans and long term vision for Verizon's global internet backbone.

- Responsible for all network infrastructure for the Verizon digital media integration lab including automating network changes in the lab. Primarily dealt with Juniper SRX series firewalls, Juniper MX series routers and Arista modular switches.
- Developed network architecture plans for several Verizon Digital Media Services (VDMS) projects.
 Architecture plans included vlan layouts, MPLS VPN overlay design, BGP policy design and multicast content delivery architecture.
- Worked with other members of the team to research Software Designed Networking (SDN) and Network Function Virtualization (NFV) for long term global network plan. Lab tested technology including OpenFlow and VXLAN. Worked with team to develop initial concept of a virtualized BGP route reflector.

Network Computing Security

Principal Member of Technical Staff

Colorado Springs, CO MARCH 2005 - MAY 2012

- Responsible for security review of network and application architecture for Verizon Digital Media Services. This included approving network architecture documents and application architecture documents. Required to participate in a leadership position in cross functional technical teams to build digital media services for a projected \$500B industry.
- Responsible for reviewing and approving enterprise firewall change requests. Responsibilities included handling request escalations and assisting in dispute resolution regarding policy interpretation.
- Technical team lead for design and development of a distributed VPN system for use accessing internal protected network segments. This system utilized Juniper Unified Access Control for managing several Juniper SSG firewalls. Additionally responsible for designing and implementing enterprise self-service system to facilitate delegated management of VPN access rules.
- Responsible for team managing Verizon Business enterprise VPN plant consisting of 20 Nortel Contivity VPN servers. We had almost zero unplanned downtime and routinely terminated approximately 35.000 concurrent IPSec sessions.

- Responsible for design and development of MAC and IP address correlation tool for real-time IP ownership resolution. This tool was used by most of Verizon Business' security and operations personnel during routine network tasks as well as rapid security incident response
- Tool development for security assessment and auditing. These tools were mostly Perl scripts for parsing various network configs and reporting on security issues. Some tools were developed ondemand during rapid incident response
- Development of Access Control List database for tracking changes to several thousand router based ACLs. System was written in Java utilizing Spring MVC, Hibernate, MySQL and a custom written RCS back-end

CENDANT CORPORATION Network Engineer

Greenwood Village, CO
DECEMBER 2004 - MARCH 2005

Network Operations - Premier Support Team

Network Operations position required working with customers and other teams to resolve network issues and perform network maintenance. Responsible for troubleshooting network problems including transport and routing issues. The premier support team was responsible for working with high profile customers.

Young Life Network Engineer Colorado Springs, CO JULY 2003 - OCTOBER 2004

Network Operations

Responsible for overall network design, management and operation of the Young Life service center network and remote office networks. This included management of employee and site-to-site site vpn, office switch fabric design, intrustion detection and network monitorring.

WORLDCOM Network Engineer Colorado Springs, CO DEC 1999 - JULY 2003

Internal Data Network Support Center

Worked in the network operation center for the MCI/WorldCom Internal Data Network. Responsible for triaging and troubleshooting network trouble tickets including issues with BGP, OSPF, spanning-tree, data center switch fabrics and transport circuits. Also responsible for creating and maintaining various network maintanence and operational Perl scripts.